

□ (929) 888-2780 | immy.h.cheung@gmail.com | imjhcheung | imjhcheung

Summary_

Full stack web developer with experience in Ruby, Javascript, Rails, React, and PostgreSQL. My previous experience as a QA Analyst has powered my passion for working with products and solving issues in code and with code.

Technical Skills

Programming Ruby, Javascript

Backend Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, REST API, PostgreSQL, SQL React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Semantic UI Frontend

Phaser3, Boardgame.io, LaTeX, Object Oriented Programming, Functional Programming

Technical Projects

Almost Simply One Github Demo

A WEB ADAPTATION OF Just One BOARD GAME

· Utilized open source Javascript framework Boardgame.io for game logic, real-time communication, and state management between clients

• Implemented user interface using React and Redux with Semantic UI React for styling

Click Runner JS

A VIDEO GAME WITH AUTORUNNER AND CLICKER GAME ELEMENTS

Demo

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for games and users using a PostgreSQL database
- Utilized *Phaser 3* Javascript Game Framework for game logic, stage management, and animations
- Implemented user interface using Vanilla Javascript and Phaser 3

TrubyaRails

A VIDEO GAME WITH TRIVIA QUESTIONS AND PICTURE GUESSING ELEMENTS

- Developed with Rails backend and frontend using a PostgreSQL database
- Scraped OpenTrivia API for trivia questions
- Implemented user interface with Rails ERB and HTML5 with Bootstrap and SASS CSS for styling

Back Support Frontend / Backend

A TICKETING SYSTEM APP FOR CUSTOMER SUPPORT AGENTS BASED ON Zendesk

Demo

Demo

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, messages, and tickets using a PostgreSQL database
- Implemented user interface utilizing React with Bootstrap React for styling
- · Used ActionCable to push messages and tickets through WebSockets for simultaneous client updates
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side

Work Experience

Vimeo Brooklyn, NY

Oct. 2018 - Apr. 2019 **OA ANALYST**

- · Assembled test plans and wrote test cases for Livestream Studio & Mevo, our livestream encoding software and livestreaming camera
- Performed regression testing, smoke testing, performance testing, and manual testing on our applications
- Coordinated with an international team of QA Analysts to meet test plan deadlines
- Troubleshooted & submitted issues that were discovered during testing or reported from users during beta testing and user acceptance testing

Vimeo (acquired Livestream)

Brooklyn, NY

LIVE VIDEO SUPPORT SPECIALIST Dec. 2016 - Oct. 2018

- Solved over 9500 tickets in our customer ticketing system with a 90% customer satisfaction rating
- Served as lead support agent overseeing technical escalations for Livestream Studio & Mevo
- · Troubleshooted and advised customers' livestreaming audio and video workflows
- · Wrote and updated customer facing FAQs and other internal documentation for our products

Education

Flatiron School New York, NY

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE

Oct. 2019 - Jan 2020

· Rigorous 15 week software engineering bootcamp focused on building dynamic web applications with Ruby, Rails, Javascript & React

Binghamton University BACHELOR OF ARTS, DOUBLE MAJOR IN POLITICAL SCIENCE & CHINESE STUDIES Binghamton, NY

Sept. 2013 - May 2015

• GPA: 3.70, Graduated magna cum laude

Stony Brook University

Stony Brook, NY

TRANSFERRED TO BINGHAMTON UNIVERSITY Jan. 2012 - May 2013

• GPA: 4.00

Stuyvesant High School New York, NY

REGENTS DIPLOMA Sept. 2007 - Jun. 2011